A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, New Delhi, India Office Files FA800
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, New Delhi, India Office Files
1951-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA800
0.94 Cubic Feet 2 legal document boxes
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as part of Accession 2019:063 (Box 32381).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series: Subject Files.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, reports, and grant documents from the Ford Foundation's work in India between 1952 and 1971. The files relate to the Ford Foundation's travel logistics in India (primarily connected with the Ford Foundation's private aircraft), Ford Foundation films "The Stranger" and "Gaon Sathis," agriculture programs, education programs, social science research, and community development programs.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation's New Delhi field office opened in 1952 as the Foundation's first international field office. During the early years of the field office, the Foundation focused on programs in agricultural and rural development, education, social sciences, public planning, population, and health and nutrition in India.
Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation -- India; Ford Foundation organization -- Field offices
- Subject Files, 1951-1971; 1; 0.94 Cubic Feet 2 legal document boxes
  - Aircraft - India - Reports, 1967 January-May (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Survey and Evaluation of the Ford Foundation Aircraft Operation in India
    Proposal of Services Aircraft Evaluation for the Ford Foundation
  - Aircraft - India - Benefit/Cost Analysis Ford Eagle III, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aircraft - India, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
  - Division of Overseas Activities (DOA) Grant Requests - India, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - India - Films - Ernest Kleinberg, Gaon Sathis (Friends of the Village), 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Related Materials
    For more information on the Ford Foundation films, Gaon Sathis and The Stranger, see Ford Foundation records, Audiovisual materials (FA750)
  - India - Films - Lloyd Young, The Stranger, 1953-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - India - Rural Training Centers, General File, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - India - Secondary Education Program, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - India - Village Development Programs, General File, 1954-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - B-162 - India - Social and Economic Research (Formerly All-India Social Science Research Center), 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - NY-14 Allahabad Agricultural Institute, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A-934 Government of Nepal - Village Development Project, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - A-729 Gandhi Memorial, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - India Community Development Program - B-69 Social Education Centers and Workshops, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Grant to the Government of India (05300045), 1953 April 09-1959 October 30
  - 53-101 (A-589) Indian Extension Directors' Study Tour to Japan and US (Agricultural Extension), 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - India - Public Administration - Paul Appleby Report, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Grant to The Indian Institute of Public Administration (05400117), 1954 July 19-1961 October 23
  - India - Agricultural Extension Departments in Colleges, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - India - Education Program, General, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - India - Books and Reports for India Project, 1953-1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)